# **Jacob Kenny**

New York, NY | 570-716-1763 | jacobkenny05@gmail.com GitHub | Blog | LinkedIn | Personal Site

#### **WEB ENGINEER**

Focused on problem solving to help fast-paced companies achieve results. Utilizes various technologies and stacks to find and deliver clean, innovative solutions. Bilingual in English and Spanish with exceptional client focus and communication. Experienced with Ruby on Rails and Javascript software engineering.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Front End: JavaScript | React | Redux | HTML | CSS | Sass | Bootstrap | Flexbox Back End: Ruby | Ruby on Rails | SQL | Git | PostgreSQL | JSON | Heroku | Netlify

#### **PROJECTS**

# TripTracker - GitHub | Site | Demo

Exchange rate tracking application that allows users to budget trips to foreign countries

- Utilized Rails API and PostgreSQL to obtain and store exchange rates and user data.
- Automated the process of obtaining real time exchange rate information.

# U.S. Game - Github | Site | Demo

Game programmed to reinforce users' knowledge of states' locations and trivia

- Established game logic using React to improve user experience.
- Compiled data in JSON format to use for each state.

## Image Scrambler - GitHub | Site | Demo

Tile slide puzzle game

- Defined logic with JavaScript event listeners for the maneuvering of puzzle tiles.
- Established processes for creation of game leaderboard through sorting of completed game objects.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Pennsylvania Treasury

Harrisburg, PA 10/2017 - 11/2019

Customer Service Representative

- Audited submitted forms and legal documentation for completion and accuracy.
- Fielded 40-60 calls per day from customers seeking to maximize their college savings.

**DataVerify** Pittsburgh, PA

Verification of Employment Specialist

11/2016 - 07/2017

- Obtained employment verifications from employers on behalf of mortgage lenders recognized as most accurate VoE Specialist for month of April 2017 and Employee of the Month May 2017.
- Handled all company's verifications for Spanish-speaking employers.

## **EDUCATION**

Flatiron School New York, NY Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program 12/2019 - 03/2020

**Gettysburg College** 

Gettysburg, PA B.A., Spanish; Minor, Educational Studies 08/2012 - 05/2016